Okay. So, now we'll do the same thing as we did before,
では  以前と同じことをするので
painting our weights in the neural network to better classify our points.
ニューラルネットワークの重みに色を付けて ポイントを分類しやすくします
But we're going to do it formally,
しかし正式に行うので
so fasten your seat belts because math is coming.
シートベルトを締めてください  数学がやってきます
On your left, you have a single perceptron with the input vector,
左には単一のパーセプトロンがあり 入力ベクター
the weights and the bias and the sigmoid function inside the node.
重み バイアス そしてノード内にシグモイド関数があります
And on the right, we have a formula for the prediction,
右には予測の式があり
which is the sigmoid function of the linear function of the input.
入力の線形関数のシグモイド関数です
And below, we have a formula for the error,
その下にはエラーの式があります
which is the average of all points of
これは青いポイントを表す青い項と
the blue term for the blue points and the red term for the red points.
赤いポイントを表す赤い項のすべてのポイントの平均です
And in order to descend from Mount Errorest,
またエラレスト山から下山するために
we calculate the gradient.
勾配を計算します
And the gradient is simply the vector formed by all the partial derivatives of
勾配は
the error function with respect to the weights w1 up to wn and and the bias b.
重みw1からwnまでとバイアスbに関するエラー関数のすべての偏微分によって形成されるベクターにすぎません
They correspond to these edges over here,
これらはこれらのエッジに対応します
and what do we do in a multilayer perceptron?
では 多層パーセプトロンでは何をすべきでしょう
Well, this time it's a little more complicated but it's pretty much the same thing.
今度は少し複雑ですが基本的には同じです
We have our prediction,
予測は
which is simply a composition of functions namely matrix multiplications and sigmoids.
関数 つまり行列乗算とシグモイド関数の組み合わせにすぎません
And the error function is pretty much the same,
エラー関数もほぼ同じですが
except the ŷ is a bit more complicated.
yハットが少し複雑です
And the gradient is pretty much the same thing,
勾配もほぼ同じです
it's just much, much longer.
長くなっただけです
It's a huge vector where each entry is
これは巨大なベクトルであり各エントリーが
a partial derivative of the error with respect to each of the weights.
各重みに対するエラーの偏微分です
And these just correspond to all the edges.
これらはすべてのエッジに対応しているだけです
If we want to write this more formally,
これをより正式に書きたい場合は
we recall that the prediction is a composition of sigmoids and matrix multiplications,
予測はシグモイドと行列乗算の組み合わせであることを思い出してください
where these are the matrices and
これらは行列であり
the gradient is just going to be formed by all these partial derivatives.
勾配はこれらすべての偏微分によって形成されます
Here, it looks like a matrix but in reality,
ここでは行列のように見えますが 実際には
it's just a long vector.
長いベクターにすぎません
And the gradient descent is going to do the following;
勾配降下法は次のようなことを行います
we take each weight,
各重み
w_i_j super k and we update it by adding a small number,
wijスーパーkを取り 小さな数
the learning rate times the partial derivative of E with respect to that same weight.
すなわち学習率を加え 同じ重みに対するEの偏微分を掛けることによって更新します
This is the gradient descent step,
これが勾配降下法のステップであり
so it will give us new updated weight w_i_j super k prime.
更新された新しい重みwijスーパーk素数が得られます
That step is going to give us a whole new model
このステップから 新しい重みを持ち
with new weights that will classify the point much better.
ポイントをより正確に分類するまったく新しいモデルが得られます